<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Bucharest Daily Travel &#8226; Travel Info about Romania</title>
	<atom:link href="https://bucharestdailynews.com/travel/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://bucharestdailynews.com/travel/</link>
	<description>News from Bucharest and Romania</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 May 2025 20:59:42 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.8.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://bucharestdailynews.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/cropped-bucharest-daily-news-icon-black-32x32.webp</url>
	<title>Bucharest Daily Travel &#8226; Travel Info about Romania</title>
	<link>https://bucharestdailynews.com/travel/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Romanian DAN AIR, the only EU airline operating commercial flights to Syria</title>
		<link>https://bucharestdailynews.com/romanian-dan-air-the-only-eu-airline-operating-commercial-flights-to-syria/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Cristian Hatis]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 08 May 2025 20:30:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[airport]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dan air]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://bucharestdailynews.com/?p=4755</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Scheduled commercial flights will be operated with an AIRBUS A320 aircraft with a capacity of 180 seats</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com/romanian-dan-air-the-only-eu-airline-operating-commercial-flights-to-syria/">Romanian DAN AIR, the only EU airline operating commercial flights to Syria</a> appeared first on <a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com">Bucharest Daily News</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p class="has-drop-cap">Beginning June 15, 2025, Romanian airline DAN AIR will launch regular commercial flights between Damascus and four major European destinations: <strong><a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com/metro/">Bucharest</a></strong>, Frankfurt, Berlin, and Stockholm. With this move, DAN AIR becomes the only airline based in the European Union to operate direct flights to the Syrian capital.</p>



<p>The airline&#8217;s entry into the Middle Eastern market was made possible through bilateral agreements between Romania and Syria, as well as DAN AIR’s official designation by the Romanian Ministry of Transport in late March 2025. Syrian aviation authorities approved this designation at the end of April.</p>



<p>In addition to DAN AIR, several well-known international airlines operate flights to and from Damascus, including Qatar Airways, Turkish Airlines, Royal Jordanian, and Kuwait Airways.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-route-schedule">Route Schedule:</h3>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Bucharest &#8211; Damascus &#8211; Bucharest</strong>: Six flights per week (Monday, Tuesday, Wednesday, Friday, Saturday, and Sunday);</li>



<li><strong>Damascus &#8211; Stockholm &#8211; Damascus</strong>: Two flights per week (Wednesday and Sunday);</li>



<li><strong>Damascus &#8211; Berlin &#8211; Damascus</strong>: Two flights per week (Tuesday and Saturday);</li>



<li><strong>Damascus &#8211; Frankfurt &#8211; Damascus</strong>: Two flights weekly (Monday and Friday).</li>
</ul>



<p>Founded in 2017 by Captain Dan Iuhas, DAN AIR operates both scheduled flights under its own brand from Bucharest and Bacău, as well as ACMI services for Romania&#8217;s national carrier TAROM and Blue Bird Airways in Tel Aviv. Since its founding, DAN AIR has transported over 4 million passengers.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-wp-embed is-provider-bucharest-daily-news wp-block-embed-bucharest-daily-news"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="S3TknOvP4q"><a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com/romania-is-the-minifootball-world-champion-after-a-dramatic-penalty-shootout/">Romania is the minifootball world champion after a dramatic penalty shootout</a></blockquote><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted"  title="&#8220;Romania is the minifootball world champion after a dramatic penalty shootout&#8221; &#8212; Bucharest Daily News" src="https://bucharestdailynews.com/romania-is-the-minifootball-world-champion-after-a-dramatic-penalty-shootout/embed/#?secret=DqB46hJZyd#?secret=S3TknOvP4q" data-secret="S3TknOvP4q" width="600" height="338" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe>
</div></figure>
<p>The post <a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com/romanian-dan-air-the-only-eu-airline-operating-commercial-flights-to-syria/">Romanian DAN AIR, the only EU airline operating commercial flights to Syria</a> appeared first on <a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com">Bucharest Daily News</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>United States removes Romania from Visa Waiver Program</title>
		<link>https://bucharestdailynews.com/united-states-removes-romania-from-visa-waiver-program/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Cristian Hatis]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 03 May 2025 07:09:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[traveler]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[USA]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://bucharestdailynews.com/?p=4724</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Romanian travelers will once again need to apply for tourist or business visas, a process that can take weeks or even months depending on demand and consular availability</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com/united-states-removes-romania-from-visa-waiver-program/">United States removes Romania from Visa Waiver Program</a> appeared first on <a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com">Bucharest Daily News</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p class="has-drop-cap">The United States Department of Homeland Security (DHS) announced Friday evening the removal of Romania from the Visa Waiver Program (VWP), only four months after it allowed Romanian citizens to travel to the U.S. for tourism or <a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com/money/">business</a> without a visa.</p>



<p>The DHS statement, issued in coordination with the Department of State, confirmed the revocation of Romania’s designation under the program. ”Today, the Department of Homeland Security, in consultation with the Department of State, has terminated Romania’s designation under the Visa Waiver Program,” the announcement read.</p>



<p>In an official statement, The Romanian Ministry of Foreign Affairs (MAE) emphasized that Romania had met all the necessary requirements to participate in the program, and called the U.S. decision ”disappointing and unjustified.”, expressing ”deep regret” over the move.</p>



<p>“We consider this decision to be unjustified and contrary to the strong strategic partnership between Romania and the United States,” said MAE spokesperson Andrei Zamfir. “Romania has fulfilled all technical and legal criteria for VWP inclusion, and we will continue our diplomatic efforts to restore this status.”</p>



<p>As of now, Romanian travelers will once again need to apply for tourist or business visas, a process that can take weeks or even months depending on demand and consular availability. The Romanian Embassy in Washington has said it will continue to advocate for Romania’s inclusion in the VWP and hopes the decision will be reconsidered in the near future.</p>



<p>The Visa Waiver Program enables citizens of approved countries to travel to the U.S. for up to 90 days without obtaining a visa, making it a coveted status that reflects a high degree of trust and cooperation. Romania had long campaigned for its inclusion, citing strong bilateral ties, a growing Romanian-American community, and compliance with security and travel standards.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-wp-embed is-provider-bucharest-daily-news wp-block-embed-bucharest-daily-news"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="EnM3TDrpZn"><a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com/world-bank-slashes-romanias-2025-growth-forecast-to-1-3-lowest-in-region/">World Bank slashes Romania&#8217;s 2025 growth forecast to 1.3%, lowest in region</a></blockquote><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted"  title="&#8220;World Bank slashes Romania&#8217;s 2025 growth forecast to 1.3%, lowest in region&#8221; &#8212; Bucharest Daily News" src="https://bucharestdailynews.com/world-bank-slashes-romanias-2025-growth-forecast-to-1-3-lowest-in-region/embed/#?secret=wLwuCNNPv7#?secret=EnM3TDrpZn" data-secret="EnM3TDrpZn" width="600" height="338" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe>
</div></figure>
<p>The post <a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com/united-states-removes-romania-from-visa-waiver-program/">United States removes Romania from Visa Waiver Program</a> appeared first on <a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com">Bucharest Daily News</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Investors to add 1,000 new hotel rooms in Bucharest by 2027</title>
		<link>https://bucharestdailynews.com/investors-to-add-1000-new-hotel-rooms-in-bucharest-by-2027/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Cristian Hatis]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2025 19:16:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hotel]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://bucharestdailynews.com/?p=4703</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Average daily rate finally surpassed the milestone of 100-euro, registering a 7.3% growth in 2024</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com/investors-to-add-1000-new-hotel-rooms-in-bucharest-by-2027/">Investors to add 1,000 new hotel rooms in Bucharest by 2027</a> appeared first on <a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com">Bucharest Daily News</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p class="has-drop-cap">Bucharest&#8217;s hotel market continued to recover in terms of occupancy rates in 2024, encouraging investments in new hotels. Thus by 2027 it is estimated that over 1.000 rooms will be added to the current supply in the city, according to Cushman &amp; Wakefield Echinox.</p>



<p>2025 promises to be a more fruitful year with two scheduled openings, one refurbishment and one extension. One of the most important openings of 2025 already took place: Corinthia Grand Hotel du Boulevard Bucharest at the junction of Calea Victoriei and Elisabeta Boulevard.</p>



<p>The growth of the hotel market in Bucharest in 2024 was in line with the trends in Central and Eastern Europe (Bucharest, Bratislava, Budapest, Prague, Sofia and Warsaw), with the RevPAR increasing by 11.8% versus 2023 and 12.6% versus 2019 pre-Covid level.</p>



<p>Average daily rate finally surpassed the milestone of 100-euro, registering a 7.3% growth in 2024 – faster ADR growth amongst CEE-6 capitals in 2024, while the occupancy is still lagging behind the 2019 level by 4pp.</p>



<p>In terms of transactional activity, Romania recorded around EUR 50 million in hotel investment volume in 2024, accounting for approximately 13% of total CEE-6 transaction volume of EUR 399M.</p>



<p>The 2024 investment volume represents a 93% increase versus the transaction volume achieved in 2023 and was generated by 7 transactions, out of which two in Bucharest: Hotel Ambasador, a property that will undergo a significant refurbishment, and Hotel Sir Royal.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-wp-embed is-provider-bucharest-daily-news wp-block-embed-bucharest-daily-news"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="xgj34oIN3O"><a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com/sanconfind-poiana-campina-wins-the-award-for-best-spa-treatment-program/">SanConfind Poiana Câmpina wins the award for ”Best Spa Treatment Program”</a></blockquote><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted"  title="&#8220;SanConfind Poiana Câmpina wins the award for ”Best Spa Treatment Program”&#8221; &#8212; Bucharest Daily News" src="https://bucharestdailynews.com/sanconfind-poiana-campina-wins-the-award-for-best-spa-treatment-program/embed/#?secret=8oXyaAxizX#?secret=xgj34oIN3O" data-secret="xgj34oIN3O" width="600" height="338" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe>
</div></figure>
<p>The post <a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com/investors-to-add-1000-new-hotel-rooms-in-bucharest-by-2027/">Investors to add 1,000 new hotel rooms in Bucharest by 2027</a> appeared first on <a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com">Bucharest Daily News</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Romania and Moldova to Begin Construction of First Road Bridge Over Prut River in Over 35 Years</title>
		<link>https://bucharestdailynews.com/romania-and-moldova-to-begin-construction-of-first-road-bridge-over-prut-river-in-over-35-years/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Cristian Hatis]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2025 19:47:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[construction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[moldova]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://bucharestdailynews.com/?p=4681</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The project is scheduled for completion within 24 months, encompassing six months for design and 18 months for construction</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com/romania-and-moldova-to-begin-construction-of-first-road-bridge-over-prut-river-in-over-35-years/">Romania and Moldova to Begin Construction of First Road Bridge Over Prut River in Over 35 Years</a> appeared first on <a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com">Bucharest Daily News</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p class="has-drop-cap">Romania and the Republic of Moldova are set to launch a major cross-border infrastructure project with the construction of a new road bridge over the Prut River &#8211; the first such development in more than three decades.</p>



<p>The new bridge, to be built near Ungheni, will connect Iași County in northeastern Romania with the Ungheni District in Moldova, and will cost EUR 30 million (approximately 152 million Romanian lei).</p>



<p>Its design includes two parallel structures, each stretching approximately 260 meters across the Prut River. Built with a composite steel-and-concrete deck and a continuous beam structure, the bridges will each support one direction of traffic</p>



<p>It will connect with Romania&#8217;s future A8 &#8220;Union&#8221; Motorway, which is expected to enhance access to the EU motorway network. On the Moldovan side, the bridge will integrate with the national road R1.</p>



<p>This will be the first new road bridge over the Prut River since the fall of communism, and the first such bridge constructed in 60 years. Prior to World War II, 27 bridges crossed the river — many of which were destroyed or rendered unusable during wartime and the Soviet era.</p>



<p>Both countries have ambitious plans to further enhance cross-border infrastructure. By 2030, each of Moldova&#8217;s 11 districts bordering the Prut is expected to have at least one operational road bridge. These efforts aim to facilitate smoother travel between Bucharest and Chișinău.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-wp-embed is-provider-bucharest-daily-news wp-block-embed-bucharest-daily-news"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="oepynKWxjN"><a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com/how-proud-are-romanians-of-their-nationality-what-does-it-mean-to-be-romanian/">How proud are Romanians of their nationality? What does it mean to be Romanian?</a></blockquote><iframe loading="lazy" class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted"  title="&#8220;How proud are Romanians of their nationality? What does it mean to be Romanian?&#8221; &#8212; Bucharest Daily News" src="https://bucharestdailynews.com/how-proud-are-romanians-of-their-nationality-what-does-it-mean-to-be-romanian/embed/#?secret=nnoEvV5T4e#?secret=oepynKWxjN" data-secret="oepynKWxjN" width="600" height="338" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe>
</div></figure>
<p>The post <a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com/romania-and-moldova-to-begin-construction-of-first-road-bridge-over-prut-river-in-over-35-years/">Romania and Moldova to Begin Construction of First Road Bridge Over Prut River in Over 35 Years</a> appeared first on <a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com">Bucharest Daily News</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A new airline enters the Romanian market. FLYONE to open a base in Bucharest</title>
		<link>https://bucharestdailynews.com/a-new-airline-enters-the-romanian-market-flyone-to-open-a-base-in-bucharest/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Cristian Hatis]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 19:54:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[airport]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Henri Coanda Airport]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://bucharestdailynews.com/?p=4584</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>FLYONE, an airline with 9 years of experience in the Republic of Moldova and Armenia markets, will open an operational base at ”Henri Coandă” International Airport &#8211; Otopeni this summer, marking its official debut on the Romanian market. The Otopeni base will operate two modern Airbus A320 aircraft with a 180-seat configuration, a standard aircraft [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com/a-new-airline-enters-the-romanian-market-flyone-to-open-a-base-in-bucharest/">A new airline enters the Romanian market. FLYONE to open a base in Bucharest</a> appeared first on <a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com">Bucharest Daily News</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p class="has-drop-cap">FLYONE, an airline with 9 years of experience in the Republic of Moldova and Armenia markets, will open an operational base at ”Henri Coandă” International Airport &#8211; Otopeni this summer, marking its official debut on the Romanian market.</p>



<p>The Otopeni base will operate two modern Airbus A320 aircraft with a 180-seat configuration, a standard aircraft model for European airlines. These aircraft are equipped with fly-by-wire technology, side-stick side controls, and quiet cabins.</p>



<p>FLYONE will initially fly to Verona (Italy) on Tuesdays and Fridays from 10 June 2025, to Brussels (Belgium) on Wednesdays and Saturdays from 2 July 2025, and to Tel Aviv (Israel) on Thursdays and Sundays from 5 June 2025.</p>



<p>Founded in 2016, FLYONE is the leading aviation company in the Republic of Moldova. As of 2022, the company is an IATA member and holds an Air Operator&#8217;s Certificate issued by the Civil Aviation Authority of Romania and an operating license from the Romanian Ministry of Transport.</p>



<p>In 2024, the airline carried over 2.4 million passengers, launched 14 new routes, and added three new aircraft to its fleet. It currently operates over 75 scheduled and charter routes, connecting Bucharest, Chisinau, Yerevan, Tashkent, and other cities with major destinations in Europe, the Middle East, Central Asia, and North Africa.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-wp-embed is-provider-bucharest-daily-news wp-block-embed-bucharest-daily-news"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="DbIbzcLdFA"><a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com/new-modern-tram-lines-on-exhibition-boulevard-in-northern-bucharest/">New modern tram lines on Exhibition Boulevard in Northern Bucharest</a></blockquote><iframe loading="lazy" class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted"  title="&#8220;New modern tram lines on Exhibition Boulevard in Northern Bucharest&#8221; &#8212; Bucharest Daily News" src="https://bucharestdailynews.com/new-modern-tram-lines-on-exhibition-boulevard-in-northern-bucharest/embed/#?secret=rZTCJl6VOy#?secret=DbIbzcLdFA" data-secret="DbIbzcLdFA" width="600" height="338" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe>
</div></figure>
<p>The post <a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com/a-new-airline-enters-the-romanian-market-flyone-to-open-a-base-in-bucharest/">A new airline enters the Romanian market. FLYONE to open a base in Bucharest</a> appeared first on <a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com">Bucharest Daily News</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Romania is last in Europe in terms of the number of foreign tourists. How do we compare with our neighbors?</title>
		<link>https://bucharestdailynews.com/romania-is-last-in-europe-in-terms-of-the-number-of-foreign-tourists-how-do-we-compare-with-our-neighbors/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Cristian Hatis]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 27 Mar 2025 19:36:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[foreign tourists]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[traveler]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://bucharestdailynews.com/?p=4575</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Only 2.4 million foreign tourists came to Romania last year, an increase of 11 percent compared to 2023, but the country remains last in Europe. According to ANAT data, spending on promoting Romania as a tourist destination barely exceeds EUR 1 million, while incoming tourism revenues total around EUR 1.3 billion. To compare, Romania&#8217;s southern [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com/romania-is-last-in-europe-in-terms-of-the-number-of-foreign-tourists-how-do-we-compare-with-our-neighbors/">Romania is last in Europe in terms of the number of foreign tourists. How do we compare with our neighbors?</a> appeared first on <a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com">Bucharest Daily News</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p class="has-drop-cap">Only 2.4 million foreign tourists came to Romania last year, an increase of 11 percent compared to 2023, but the country remains last in Europe. According to ANAT data, spending on promoting Romania as a tourist destination barely exceeds EUR 1 million, while incoming tourism revenues total around EUR 1.3 billion.</p>



<p>To compare, Romania&#8217;s southern neighbor Bulgaria attracted 13 million foreign tourists in 2024, spent about 20 million BGN / 10 million EUR on advertising, and earned about 14 billion BGN / 7.2 billion EUR from incoming tourism.</p>



<p><a href="https://moneybuzz.gr/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Greece</a> remains a top destination, attracting 36 million foreign tourists in 2024. It spent around 40 million euros on promotion between 2019 and 2024, and had incoming tourism receipts of around 22 billion euros in 2024, up 10% from 2023.</p>



<p>An increasingly popular destination is Albania, which attracted 11.7 million foreign tourists in 2024, an increase of 15% on the previous year, making the small Balkan republic Europe&#8217;s fastest-growing tourism destination. Albania&#8217;s incoming tourism receipts climbed to around 4.8 billion euros.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-wp-embed is-provider-bucharest-daily-news wp-block-embed-bucharest-daily-news"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="vAraLo0ElT"><a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com/presidential-elections-2025-who-are-the-11-candidates-in-the-race-for-the-cotroceni-palace/">Presidential Elections 2025. Who are the 11 candidates in the race for the Cotroceni Palace</a></blockquote><iframe loading="lazy" class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted"  title="&#8220;Presidential Elections 2025. Who are the 11 candidates in the race for the Cotroceni Palace&#8221; &#8212; Bucharest Daily News" src="https://bucharestdailynews.com/presidential-elections-2025-who-are-the-11-candidates-in-the-race-for-the-cotroceni-palace/embed/#?secret=hd5ZD4AkiH#?secret=vAraLo0ElT" data-secret="vAraLo0ElT" width="600" height="338" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe>
</div></figure>
<p>The post <a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com/romania-is-last-in-europe-in-terms-of-the-number-of-foreign-tourists-how-do-we-compare-with-our-neighbors/">Romania is last in Europe in terms of the number of foreign tourists. How do we compare with our neighbors?</a> appeared first on <a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com">Bucharest Daily News</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Historic peak! The hotel market recorded the highest number of tourists in the last three decades</title>
		<link>https://bucharestdailynews.com/historic-peak-the-hotel-market-recorded-the-highest-number-of-tourists-in-the-last-three-decades/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Cristian Hatis]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2025 19:38:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hotel]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://bucharestdailynews.com/?p=4500</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Romania's accession to the Schengen area in 2025 could further boost tourist inflows, supporting industry expansion</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com/historic-peak-the-hotel-market-recorded-the-highest-number-of-tourists-in-the-last-three-decades/">Historic peak! The hotel market recorded the highest number of tourists in the last three decades</a> appeared first on <a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com">Bucharest Daily News</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p class="has-drop-cap">Romania’s hotel market reached a record of more than 25 million overnight stays in 2024, the highest level in more than 30 years, driven by a rising number of foreign tourists and strong demand for modern hotels, according to Colliers’ annual report.</p>



<p>The number of overnight stays surpassed pre-pandemic levels by 4%, exceeding the EU average, which grew by less than 2% over the same period. This growth is driven largely by domestic tourists and the leisure sector.</p>



<p>According to Eurostat, a business traveler in Romania spent an average of EUR 333 per trip in 2023, one of the lowest values in the European Union. This amount is significantly lower than in Hungary (EUR 562) and Poland (EUR 488). However, Romania stands out with the third fastest growth rate in the EU for this indicator.</p>



<p>According to the report, which analyzed 4 and 5-star hotels in Bucharest affiliated with international brands, the average daily rate has exceeded 2019 levels, reaching over EUR 140 per night – a 21% increase in foreign currency and 27% in local currency (RON).</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-wp-embed is-provider-bucharest-daily-news wp-block-embed-bucharest-daily-news"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="s8pRsaUdNw"><a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com/new-office-space-leased-in-the-last-5-years-reached-1-million-square-meters/">New office space leased in the last 5 years reached 1 million square meters</a></blockquote><iframe loading="lazy" class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted"  title="&#8220;New office space leased in the last 5 years reached 1 million square meters&#8221; &#8212; Bucharest Daily News" src="https://bucharestdailynews.com/new-office-space-leased-in-the-last-5-years-reached-1-million-square-meters/embed/#?secret=q0YB14v63M#?secret=s8pRsaUdNw" data-secret="s8pRsaUdNw" width="600" height="338" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe>
</div></figure>
<p>The post <a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com/historic-peak-the-hotel-market-recorded-the-highest-number-of-tourists-in-the-last-three-decades/">Historic peak! The hotel market recorded the highest number of tourists in the last three decades</a> appeared first on <a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com">Bucharest Daily News</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Record number of passengers for Romanian airports in 2024. Over 26 million!</title>
		<link>https://bucharestdailynews.com/record-number-of-passengers-for-romanian-airports-in-2024-over-26-million/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Cristian Hatis]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 16:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[airport]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Henri Coanda Airport]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://bucharestdailynews.com/?p=4079</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Henri Coandă Otopeni-Bucharest Airport remains the busiest airport in 2024, with almost 16 million passengers, more than half of the total number recorded</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com/record-number-of-passengers-for-romanian-airports-in-2024-over-26-million/">Record number of passengers for Romanian airports in 2024. Over 26 million!</a> appeared first on <a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com">Bucharest Daily News</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p class="has-drop-cap">Air passenger traffic recorded by Romanian airports during 2024 increased by almost 6 percent compared to 2023 figures. Thus, 26,033,372 passengers transited Romanian airports last year. Compared to 2019, air traffic increased by 12 percent, data from the Romanian Airports Association show.</p>



<p>The upward trend in passenger numbers on international flights continued (+7% in 2024 compared to 2023), as did the decrease in passengers on domestic flights (-6% in 2024 compared to 2023). Air cargo traffic increased by 4%, and the number of aircraft movements (landings and take-offs) increased by 3%.</p>



<p>Of all passengers transiting through local airports since Romania&#8217;s accession to the Schengen airspace, as of March 31, 70 percent traveled within the Schengen area and 30 percent to/from non-Schengen destinations.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-which-are-the-busiest-romanian-airports">Which are the busiest Romanian airports</h2>



<p>Henri Coandă Otopeni-Bucharest Airport remains the busiest airport in 2024, with almost 16 million passengers, more than half of the total number recorded. The capital&#8217;s second airport, Băneasa Airport, was transited by 107,087 passengers in 2024.</p>



<p>Romania&#8217;s second-largest airport remains Cluj with 3,266 million passengers, followed by Iasi with 2,197 million passengers, and Train Vuia Airport in Timișoara with 1,324 million passengers.</p>



<p>The airports of Suceava &#8211; 746,600 passengers, Sibiu &#8211; 573,918, Bacău &#8211; 559,644, Craiova &#8211; 424,976, Brasov &#8211; 227,900, Târgu Mureș &#8211; 213,312, Oradea &#8211; 169,166, Constanța &#8211; 109,317, Băneasa &#8211; 107,087, surpassed the threshold of 100.000 passengers.</p>



<p>The lowest number of passengers transited through the airports of Tulcea, only 1,621 passengers during the whole year, Arad &#8211; 15,270 passengers, Satu Mare &#8211; 70,206, and Maramureș &#8211; 86,928 passengers.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-wp-embed is-provider-bucharest-daily-news wp-block-embed-bucharest-daily-news"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="JP5omYKuYt"><a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com/romania-is-still-one-of-the-most-affordable-property-markets-in-central-and-eastern-europe/">Romania is still one of the most affordable property markets in Central and Eastern Europe</a></blockquote><iframe loading="lazy" class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted"  title="&#8220;Romania is still one of the most affordable property markets in Central and Eastern Europe&#8221; &#8212; Bucharest Daily News" src="https://bucharestdailynews.com/romania-is-still-one-of-the-most-affordable-property-markets-in-central-and-eastern-europe/embed/#?secret=GcyAjFCyq5#?secret=JP5omYKuYt" data-secret="JP5omYKuYt" width="600" height="338" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe>
</div></figure>
<p>The post <a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com/record-number-of-passengers-for-romanian-airports-in-2024-over-26-million/">Record number of passengers for Romanian airports in 2024. Over 26 million!</a> appeared first on <a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com">Bucharest Daily News</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>What foreign tourists visiting Bucharest want to see and which restaurants they go to</title>
		<link>https://bucharestdailynews.com/what-information-did-foreign-tourists-search-about-bucharest-in-2024/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Cristian Hatis]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 17:28:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[foreign tourists]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://bucharestdailynews.com/?p=4065</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>British tourists searched for ”Bucharest Therme” and ”Fountain Show“, Americans are interested in „locations where the series Wednesday was filmed”, traditional Romanian cuisine and restaurants, while Christmas markets, concerts and festivals attracted Bulgarians, a Visit Bucharest study shows. The most searched attractions (including seasonal ones) and tourist attractions are Bucharest Christmas Market, Bucharest Fountain Show, [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com/what-information-did-foreign-tourists-search-about-bucharest-in-2024/">What foreign tourists visiting Bucharest want to see and which restaurants they go to</a> appeared first on <a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com">Bucharest Daily News</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p class="has-drop-cap">British tourists searched for ”Bucharest Therme” and ”Fountain Show“, Americans are interested in „locations where the series Wednesday was filmed”, traditional Romanian cuisine and restaurants, while Christmas markets, concerts and festivals attracted Bulgarians, a Visit Bucharest study shows.</p>



<p>The most searched attractions (including seasonal ones) and <a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com/travel/">tourist attractions</a> are Bucharest Christmas Market, Bucharest Fountain Show, Old Town, Parliament Palace, and Therme Bucharest.</p>



<p>The most searched museums/exhibitions in 2024 are Ceaușescu House, Village Museum, the „Salvador Dali Universe” Exhibition at Gabroveni Inn, the”Grigore Antipa” National Museum, and the Romanian National Museum of Art.</p>



<p>Most searched restaurants in <a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com/">Bucharest</a> by foreign tourists are Caru’ cu Bere, Berăria H, Hanu’ lui Manuc, Linea Closer to the Moon, City Grill (Primăverii&nbsp;&amp;&nbsp;Covaci), and NOR on the 36th floor of the SkyTower building.</p>



<p>According to data on access from abroad, most tourists search for information about Bucharest from the United Kingdom, United States, Germany, Bulgaria, Italy, <a href="https://moneybuzz.gr/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Greece</a>, Israel, Netherlands, and France.</p>



<p>The analysis was conducted on 750,000 views on the web platform and over 10 million views of posts on associated social accounts counted from January 1 to December 20, 2024.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-wp-embed is-provider-bucharest-daily-news wp-block-embed-bucharest-daily-news"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="yFlq5MRtnW"><a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com/no-more-borders-romania-and-bulgaria-are-full-members-of-schengen/">NO MORE BORDERS! Romania and Bulgaria are full members of Schengen</a></blockquote><iframe loading="lazy" class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted"  title="&#8220;NO MORE BORDERS! Romania and Bulgaria are full members of Schengen&#8221; &#8212; Bucharest Daily News" src="https://bucharestdailynews.com/no-more-borders-romania-and-bulgaria-are-full-members-of-schengen/embed/#?secret=Hq6sQ2eCAn#?secret=yFlq5MRtnW" data-secret="yFlq5MRtnW" width="600" height="338" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe>
</div></figure>
<p>The post <a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com/what-information-did-foreign-tourists-search-about-bucharest-in-2024/">What foreign tourists visiting Bucharest want to see and which restaurants they go to</a> appeared first on <a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com">Bucharest Daily News</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>New Park &#038; Ride near Cluj-Napoca ”Avram Iancu” International Airport with 889 spaces</title>
		<link>https://bucharestdailynews.com/new-park-ride-near-cluj-napoca-avram-iancu-international-airport-with-889-spaces/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Cristian Hatis]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 20:04:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[airport]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cluj]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[parking]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://bucharestdailynews.com/?p=4040</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>A new parking lot, with 889 spaces, will be opened in January near Cluj-Napoca&#8217;s ”Avram Iancu” International Airport. Visitors to Cluj can leave their cars here and then use public transportation in the city. The new parking lot next to the ”Avram Iancu” International Airport includes 788 parking spaces for cars, 30 parking spaces for [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com/new-park-ride-near-cluj-napoca-avram-iancu-international-airport-with-889-spaces/">New Park &amp; Ride near Cluj-Napoca ”Avram Iancu” International Airport with 889 spaces</a> appeared first on <a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com">Bucharest Daily News</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p class="has-drop-cap">A new parking lot, with 889 spaces, will be opened in January near Cluj-Napoca&#8217;s ”Avram Iancu” International Airport. Visitors to Cluj can leave their cars here and then use public transportation in the city.</p>



<p>The new parking lot next to the ”Avram Iancu” International Airport includes 788 parking spaces for cars, 30 parking spaces for electric vehicles, including charging stations, 39 parking spaces for disabled people, 24 dedicated parking spaces for taxi drivers, 8 parking bays and a modern terminal for coaches.</p>



<p>Parking fees have been designed to encourage people to leave their cars in the airport area and use public transport in the city: the first 10 minutes are free; for 6 hours, the cost is only 2 lei (around 0.4 euros), and for 12 hours, the cost is 5 lei (1 EUR).</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-wp-embed is-provider-bucharest-daily-news wp-block-embed-bucharest-daily-news"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="7YBLKmytny"><a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com/second-europes-most-beautiful-and-largest-christmas-market-is-in-craiova/">Second Europe’s most beautiful and largest Christmas Market is in Craiova</a></blockquote><iframe loading="lazy" class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted"  title="&#8220;Second Europe’s most beautiful and largest Christmas Market is in Craiova&#8221; &#8212; Bucharest Daily News" src="https://bucharestdailynews.com/second-europes-most-beautiful-and-largest-christmas-market-is-in-craiova/embed/#?secret=nziypbsiZ7#?secret=7YBLKmytny" data-secret="7YBLKmytny" width="600" height="338" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe>
</div></figure>
<p>The post <a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com/new-park-ride-near-cluj-napoca-avram-iancu-international-airport-with-889-spaces/">New Park &amp; Ride near Cluj-Napoca ”Avram Iancu” International Airport with 889 spaces</a> appeared first on <a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com">Bucharest Daily News</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
