<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Bucharest Daily News Life &#8226; Lifestyle in Bucharest &amp; Romania</title>
	<atom:link href="https://bucharestdailynews.com/life/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://bucharestdailynews.com/life/</link>
	<description>News from Bucharest and Romania</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 May 2025 08:20:10 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.8.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://bucharestdailynews.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/cropped-bucharest-daily-news-icon-black-32x32.webp</url>
	<title>Bucharest Daily News Life &#8226; Lifestyle in Bucharest &amp; Romania</title>
	<link>https://bucharestdailynews.com/life/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>A$AP ROCKY joins an explosive lineup of artists at ”Beach, Please!” festival</title>
		<link>https://bucharestdailynews.com/aap-rocky-joins-an-explosive-lineup-of-artists-at-beach-please-festival/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Cristian Hatis]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 20:37:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[beach]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[festival]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://bucharestdailynews.com/?p=4719</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Interest in the festival has exceeded all expectations as over 100,000 tickets have been sold so far</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com/aap-rocky-joins-an-explosive-lineup-of-artists-at-beach-please-festival/">A$AP ROCKY joins an explosive lineup of artists at ”Beach, Please!” festival</a> appeared first on <a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com">Bucharest Daily News</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p class="has-drop-cap">Global superstar and one of the most influential figures in hip-hop, A$AP Rocky, has officially confirmed his appearance at the ”Beach, Please!” festival’s fourth edition, marking a historic moment for the music scene in Romania and Eastern Europe.</p>



<p>Known for hits like „Praise The Lord”, „Fashion Killa”, and „L$D”, and for his unmistakable style, A$AP Rocky will bring the authentic New York vibe to the Black Sea beach between July 9-13, 2025. He is also a fashion icon, having significantly influenced global pop culture over the past decade.</p>



<p>This year ”Beach, Please!” lineup is completed by international stars 21 Savage, performing for the first time in Romania, Young Thug, Lil Baby, Peso Pluma, Yeat, Ken Carson, NLE Choppa, 6IX9INE, Denzel Curry, Lazer Dim 700, Ferg, Swae Lee, Lil Pump, Lil Tjay, NAV, Lil Tecca, and Romanian artists INNA and Cojo.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-2025-to-mark-a-record-breaking-edition-for-the-festival">2025 to mark a record-breaking edition for the festival</h2>



<p>Interest in the festival has exceeded all expectations as over 100,000 tickets have been sold so far, making &#8220;Beach, Please!&#8221; the largest urban music event in Eastern Europe. Organizers had to pause ticket sales in early April to adapt logistics at the massive number of attendees.</p>



<p>Prices start at EUR 200 for General Access or EUR 400 for the Ultra VIP + Golden Circle 5 Day Pass but will rise as tickets continue to sell out. This year, a 6-hectare food court promenade, a brand-new parking area, and upgraded roads to ease traffic flow were added.</p>



<p>This year&#8217;s edition is expected to bring over EUR 60 million to the local economy in Costinești commune through participants’ spending on accommodation, transportation, restaurants, services, and related activities.</p>



<p>Additionally, a shuttle bus system will be available, connecting Costinești with the major southern seaside resorts: Mangalia, Saturn, Venus, Neptun, Olimp, Eforie Sud, Eforie Nord, and Constanța.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-wp-embed is-provider-bucharest-daily-news wp-block-embed-bucharest-daily-news"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="alYTFz1tXn"><a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com/lucky-romania-to-play-in-one-of-the-most-accessible-groups-at-euro-2024/">Lucky draw! Romania to play in one of the most accessible groups at EURO 2024</a></blockquote><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted"  title="&#8220;Lucky draw! Romania to play in one of the most accessible groups at EURO 2024&#8221; &#8212; Bucharest Daily News" src="https://bucharestdailynews.com/lucky-romania-to-play-in-one-of-the-most-accessible-groups-at-euro-2024/embed/#?secret=HhoecK2TOw#?secret=alYTFz1tXn" data-secret="alYTFz1tXn" width="600" height="338" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe>
</div></figure>
<p>The post <a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com/aap-rocky-joins-an-explosive-lineup-of-artists-at-beach-please-festival/">A$AP ROCKY joins an explosive lineup of artists at ”Beach, Please!” festival</a> appeared first on <a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com">Bucharest Daily News</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Half of young people dine out at least once a week, especially for lunch</title>
		<link>https://bucharestdailynews.com/half-of-young-people-dine-out-at-least-once-a-week-especially-for-lunch/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Cristian Hatis]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 13:49:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[restaurant]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://bucharestdailynews.com/?p=4541</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Half of young people (54%) dine out at least once a week, with lunch being their preferred time for a restaurant visit. Additionally, 63% consider location very important as restaurants in central areas, with distinctive designs and cozy atmospheres, are favored by young people aged 18 to 40, according to a City Grill analysis. Young [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com/half-of-young-people-dine-out-at-least-once-a-week-especially-for-lunch/">Half of young people dine out at least once a week, especially for lunch</a> appeared first on <a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com">Bucharest Daily News</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p class="has-drop-cap">Half of young people (54%) dine out at least once a week, with lunch being their preferred time for a restaurant visit. Additionally, 63% consider location very important as restaurants in central areas, with distinctive designs and cozy atmospheres, are favored by young people aged 18 to 40, according to a City Grill analysis.</p>



<p>Young people aged 18-24 go out frequently, favoring cafés, brunch spots, and outings with friends, visiting restaurants about once a week. For them, dining is more of a social experience than a culinary one. They prefer social spaces and a curated international menu – not too extensive – spending between 150-300 RON per outing.</p>



<p>Those aged 25-30 frequent pubs and lounges 2-3 times per week. They value their relationship with the staff, preferring friendly yet ”cool” and knowledgeable waiters. They also prefer restaurants in natural settings where they can take a walk afterward, with budgets ranging from 200 RON (for drinks only) to 400 RON when dining out.</p>



<p>The 31-40 age group prioritizes food and service quality, dining out daily for lunch and 2-3 times per week in the evening. For this segment, a fine dining experience is complemented by location, atmosphere, music, and the restaurant’s story – factors that contribute to customer loyalty. Their budget for a dining experience varies between 300 and 500 RON, depending on the time spent at the restaurant.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-wp-embed is-provider-bucharest-daily-news wp-block-embed-bucharest-daily-news"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="X9ZlIE8HLR"><a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com/labor-shortage-to-reach-over-150000-unfilled-positions-more-foreign-workers-coming/">Labor shortage to reach over 150,000 unfilled positions. More foreign workers coming</a></blockquote><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted"  title="&#8220;Labor shortage to reach over 150,000 unfilled positions. More foreign workers coming&#8221; &#8212; Bucharest Daily News" src="https://bucharestdailynews.com/labor-shortage-to-reach-over-150000-unfilled-positions-more-foreign-workers-coming/embed/#?secret=d7KIf73MZp#?secret=X9ZlIE8HLR" data-secret="X9ZlIE8HLR" width="600" height="338" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe>
</div></figure>
<p>The post <a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com/half-of-young-people-dine-out-at-least-once-a-week-especially-for-lunch/">Half of young people dine out at least once a week, especially for lunch</a> appeared first on <a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com">Bucharest Daily News</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Half of Romanians aged over 40 have dental treatments with heavy metal fillings</title>
		<link>https://bucharestdailynews.com/half-of-romanians-aged-over-40-have-dental-treatments-with-heavy-metal-fillings/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Cristian Hatis]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 22 Feb 2025 09:46:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[health]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://bucharestdailynews.com/?p=4092</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>More than half of Romanians over the age of 40 who have had cavities treated over the years reported at least one intervention with a heavy metal amalgam – based on Mercury, Beryllium, Nickel or Copper, a dangerous technique used mainly between the 1980s and early 2000s. According to a decision of the European Parliament [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com/half-of-romanians-aged-over-40-have-dental-treatments-with-heavy-metal-fillings/">Half of Romanians aged over 40 have dental treatments with heavy metal fillings</a> appeared first on <a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com">Bucharest Daily News</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p class="has-drop-cap">More than half of Romanians over the age of 40 who have had cavities treated over the years reported at least one intervention with a heavy metal amalgam – based on Mercury, Beryllium, Nickel or Copper, a dangerous technique used mainly between the 1980s and early 2000s.</p>



<p>According to a decision of the European Parliament in 2024, heavy metal-based fillings have been banned from January 1, 2025 across the European Union due to the increased risk to human health. Yet around 40 tons of mercury was still being used in dental treatments in the EU last year. &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Mercury is a highly toxic chemical that poses a threat to both human health and the environment. Exposure to high levels of mercury can cause damage to the brain, lungs, kidneys and immune system, the LIFE Group data shows.</p>



<p>According to Cristina Obreja M.D., Copper – increases oxidative stress, affecting cellular health, Nickel – is a powerful allergen that can cause serious reactions, Beryllium, Cadmium, Arsenic or Chromium – are carcinogenic substances, while Mercury in amalgam fillings evaporates, enters the bloodstream, attacks the kidneys and nervous system. &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Laser treatment of a cavity in LIFE Dental Spa or VIVO Dental clinics varies between 60 and 120 EUR, depending on the area or the promotional packages available.&nbsp;Dental treatment, when it’s too late to improve the problem, can cost the patient up to EUR 1000 for a single tooth.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-wp-embed is-provider-bucharest-daily-news wp-block-embed-bucharest-daily-news"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="kxI5ATvWXR"><a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com/over-a-third-of-students-are-affected-by-numerical-illiteracy/">Over a third of students are affected by numerical illiteracy</a></blockquote><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted"  title="&#8220;Over a third of students are affected by numerical illiteracy&#8221; &#8212; Bucharest Daily News" src="https://bucharestdailynews.com/over-a-third-of-students-are-affected-by-numerical-illiteracy/embed/#?secret=ihF1z81wPp#?secret=kxI5ATvWXR" data-secret="kxI5ATvWXR" width="600" height="338" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe>
</div></figure>
<p>The post <a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com/half-of-romanians-aged-over-40-have-dental-treatments-with-heavy-metal-fillings/">Half of Romanians aged over 40 have dental treatments with heavy metal fillings</a> appeared first on <a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com">Bucharest Daily News</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A big part of Romanians don’t want to learn, they just want the paper that ”certifies” their skills</title>
		<link>https://bucharestdailynews.com/a-big-part-of-romanians-dont-want-to-learn-they-just-want-the-paper-that-certifies-their-skills/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Cristian Hatis]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2025 18:37:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[school]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://bucharestdailynews.com/?p=4085</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Only 10% of Romanians with Internet access have taken some form of online education, which places Romania in last place in the EU, far from the leader Ireland (61% of users)</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com/a-big-part-of-romanians-dont-want-to-learn-they-just-want-the-paper-that-certifies-their-skills/">A big part of Romanians don’t want to learn, they just want the paper that ”certifies” their skills</a> appeared first on <a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com">Bucharest Daily News</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p class="has-drop-cap">Although they enroll in training courses in various fields, some Romanians have a harmful mentality &#8211; they do not want to learn, but only want to obtain an accredited diploma, which will ”certify” them of skills that they have not acquired, shows an analysis of the behavior of course consumers carried out by APSAP.</p>



<p>In context, Romanians have little interest in developing new skills and digital abilities that would help them advance professionally, ranking last in the EU in online education, according to Eurostat data.</p>



<p>Thus, only 10% of Romanians with Internet access have taken some form of online education, which places Romania in last place in the EU, far from the lead held by Ireland (61% of users), the Netherlands (59%) or Finland (53%).</p>



<p>In addition, Romanians are deficient in developing new skills because they abandon training courses. Over 30% of those enrolled drop out before the training begins, most often when people find out that they have to submit documents proving their studies, they have to allocate real-time for theoretical and practical training, there are assessments and an exam at the end.</p>



<p>The interest in developing new skills is correlated with the low level of education of the majority of the population. According to Eurostat, Romania ranks last in the European Union in terms of the number of young people with university degrees, with only 1 in 4 young people completing a form of higher education. At EU level, 42% of people aged 25 to 34 are university graduates.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-wp-embed is-provider-bucharest-daily-news wp-block-embed-bucharest-daily-news"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="J816p26YT6"><a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com/about-2-mln-romanians-to-cross-the-threshold-of-dental-clinics-in-december/">About 2 mln. Romanians to cross the threshold of dental clinics in December</a></blockquote><iframe loading="lazy" class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted"  title="&#8220;About 2 mln. Romanians to cross the threshold of dental clinics in December&#8221; &#8212; Bucharest Daily News" src="https://bucharestdailynews.com/about-2-mln-romanians-to-cross-the-threshold-of-dental-clinics-in-december/embed/#?secret=IzLvt1Fkv8#?secret=J816p26YT6" data-secret="J816p26YT6" width="600" height="338" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe>
</div></figure>
<p>The post <a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com/a-big-part-of-romanians-dont-want-to-learn-they-just-want-the-paper-that-certifies-their-skills/">A big part of Romanians don’t want to learn, they just want the paper that ”certifies” their skills</a> appeared first on <a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com">Bucharest Daily News</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>SkyTower launches “BIG CITY LIGHTS”, a public photography contest</title>
		<link>https://bucharestdailynews.com/skytower-launches-big-city-lights-a-public-photography-contest/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Cristian Hatis]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 09:52:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[office]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[skytower]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://bucharestdailynews.com/?p=4062</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>SkyTower Bucharest launches a new public photography contest with the theme “BIG CITY LIGHTS”. The contest is the fifth public competition launched as part of the “SKY&#8217;S THE LIMIT” programme initiated by SkyTower in 2023. The “BIG CITY LIGHTS” photo competition will award pictures taken between December 11th 2024 and January 31st 2025 with substantial cash [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com/skytower-launches-big-city-lights-a-public-photography-contest/">SkyTower launches “BIG CITY LIGHTS”, a public photography contest</a> appeared first on <a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com">Bucharest Daily News</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p class="has-drop-cap">SkyTower Bucharest launches a new public photography contest with the theme “BIG CITY LIGHTS”. The contest is the fifth public competition launched as part of the “SKY&#8217;S THE LIMIT” programme<strong> </strong>initiated by SkyTower in 2023.</p>



<p>The “BIG CITY LIGHTS” photo competition will award pictures taken between December 11<sup>th</sup> 2024 and January 31<sup>st</sup> 2025 with substantial cash prizes ranging from €250 to €1,000. The total value of the BIG CITY LIGHTS COMPETITION prizes is EUR 3.500.</p>



<p>Six prizes will be awarded within the Big City Lights contest, three of which will be awarded to the general public, and three will be awarded to community members the SkyTower and ByTower buildings.</p>



<p>The first prize for each category is EUR 1,000, the second prize for each category is EUR 500, and the third prize for each category is EUR 250. Each participant can enter between 1 and 3 photographs, which must be uploaded to social media platforms.</p>



<p></p>



<p></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com/skytower-launches-big-city-lights-a-public-photography-contest/">SkyTower launches “BIG CITY LIGHTS”, a public photography contest</a> appeared first on <a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com">Bucharest Daily News</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>About 2 mln. Romanians to cross the threshold of dental clinics in December</title>
		<link>https://bucharestdailynews.com/about-2-mln-romanians-to-cross-the-threshold-of-dental-clinics-in-december/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Cristian Hatis]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 20:33:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dentist]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[health]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://bucharestdailynews.com/?p=4043</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Prices for dental care in Romania are up to 80% more affordable than in the West </p>
<p>The post <a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com/about-2-mln-romanians-to-cross-the-threshold-of-dental-clinics-in-december/">About 2 mln. Romanians to cross the threshold of dental clinics in December</a> appeared first on <a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com">Bucharest Daily News</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p class="has-drop-cap">Approximately 2 million Romanians will cross the threshold of dental clinics during December 2024 to undergo various dental treatments, according to data from LIFE Dental Spa and VIVO Dental.</p>



<p>Thus, LIFE Group also estimates that the threshold of dental clinics will be crossed in December, on average, by about 250 patients per dental unit out of the 7,800 dental clinics across the country, resulting in a total of about two million patients.</p>



<p>At the end of November, the number of appointments for December was already 20% higher than in a typical month, and this was largely due to the arrival of relatives who had gone abroad, bonuses received by employees in the last month of the year or plans to pay more attention to the quality of life.</p>



<p>A significant increase this year in the number of patients is observed from Romanians coming to the country during December, where over 250,000 Romanians from the Diaspora are expected both for the holiday period and to spend time with family and friends.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-prices-for-dental-care-in-romania-are-up-to-80-more-affordable-than-in-the-west">Prices for dental care in Romania are up to 80% more affordable than in the West </h2>



<p>For a laser treatment of a cavity, in Romania, prices start from 300 RON (EUR 60), as compared to Western Europe where prices can vary between EUR 100 to EUR 300, depending on the country and clinic chosen.</p>



<p>In Romania, the classic hygiene package (professional scaling and brushing) is about 250 RON (EUR 50). In Western Europe, prices for similar procedures can vary between EUR 80 to EUR 150, depending on location and dental clinic. </p>



<p>Also, a dental implant costs about 2.000 RON (EUR 400) in Romania, and in Western Europe, prices for a single dental implant start at around EUR 1.000 and can increase significantly, depending on the complexity of the case and the materials used. </p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-wp-embed is-provider-bucharest-daily-news wp-block-embed-bucharest-daily-news"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="tR1AOYV0Cw"><a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com/two-female-physicians-accused-of-premeditated-murder-arrested/">Two female physicians accused of premeditated murder, arrested</a></blockquote><iframe loading="lazy" class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted"  title="&#8220;Two female physicians accused of premeditated murder, arrested&#8221; &#8212; Bucharest Daily News" src="https://bucharestdailynews.com/two-female-physicians-accused-of-premeditated-murder-arrested/embed/#?secret=zRyvDykVcV#?secret=tR1AOYV0Cw" data-secret="tR1AOYV0Cw" width="600" height="338" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe>
</div></figure>



<p></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com/about-2-mln-romanians-to-cross-the-threshold-of-dental-clinics-in-december/">About 2 mln. Romanians to cross the threshold of dental clinics in December</a> appeared first on <a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com">Bucharest Daily News</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Christmas Fair in Sibiu will turn on its lights on November 15</title>
		<link>https://bucharestdailynews.com/christmas-fair-in-sibiu-will-turn-on-its-lights-on-november-15/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Cristian Hatis]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 10:41:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[christmas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[christmas market]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://bucharestdailynews.com/?p=3487</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>At this year's edition of the Christmas Fair, there will be 120 exhibitors from 36 counties of Romania, but also from Israel, Hungary and Italy</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com/christmas-fair-in-sibiu-will-turn-on-its-lights-on-november-15/">Christmas Fair in Sibiu will turn on its lights on November 15</a> appeared first on <a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com">Bucharest Daily News</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p class="has-drop-cap">Christmas Unboxed, this year’s theme for the 17th edition of the Christmas Fair in Sibiu, will turn on its lights on November 15 and until January 5, 2025. The event will expand and take place in several places in the city.</p>



<p>In Piața Mare, under an installation of tens of thousands of lights, a terrace will be placed where visitors can enjoy the hot drinks and dishes from the fair. Also here you will find the panoramic Ferris wheel, 22 meters high, and the natural ice rink.</p>



<p>With an area of ​​600 square meters and a capacity of 300 people, it’s one of the main attractions every year. In Piața Mare, in addition to the 120 exhibitors and artisans, you will also find Santa&#8217;s Workshop.</p>



<p>Santa&#8217;s Workshop has a variety of activities for children, including paper making and mosaic workshops. Visited by over 4,000 kids every edition, Santa&#8217;s Workshop becomes the place where the little ones can learn new things in a fun and festive way.</p>



<p>In Piața Mică, visitors will enjoy Santa&#8217;s Land. There will be a carousel and a children&#8217;s train, children will be able to take virtual rides with Santa&#8217;s sleigh and a spectacular wood cabin where visitors can rest and warm up. </p>



<p>On the facades of the buildings in Piața Mică there will be colorful projections in the spirit of the Winter Holidays, spread over thousands of square meters. Further, the route continues in Huet Square where it will be possible to walk through a spectacular installation with illuminated trees.</p>



<p>More than 300,000 tourists are expected at this year&#8217;s edition. The period in which the fair takes place represents the second tourist season of the city of Sibiu, when the demand for accommodation reaches the limit of the current offer.</p>



<p>The Christmas Fair in Sibiu was launched in 2007, being the first fair of its kind in Romania organized according to a European model and also the longest-running, being organized by the same team. </p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-wp-embed is-provider-bucharest-daily-news wp-block-embed-bucharest-daily-news"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="3EH7z1Kd56"><a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com/finnish-fast-food-chain-hesburger-opens-its-fourth-restaurant-in-romania/">Finnish fast-food chain Hesburger opens its fourth restaurant in Romania</a></blockquote><iframe loading="lazy" class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted"  title="&#8220;Finnish fast-food chain Hesburger opens its fourth restaurant in Romania&#8221; &#8212; Bucharest Daily News" src="https://bucharestdailynews.com/finnish-fast-food-chain-hesburger-opens-its-fourth-restaurant-in-romania/embed/#?secret=3rz5Im49zx#?secret=3EH7z1Kd56" data-secret="3EH7z1Kd56" width="600" height="338" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe>
</div></figure>
<p>The post <a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com/christmas-fair-in-sibiu-will-turn-on-its-lights-on-november-15/">Christmas Fair in Sibiu will turn on its lights on November 15</a> appeared first on <a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com">Bucharest Daily News</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Romania&#8217;s most attractive cities? Brasov, Cluj-Napoca and Oradea</title>
		<link>https://bucharestdailynews.com/romanias-most-attractive-cities-brasov-cluj-napoca-and-oradea/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Cristian Hatis]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2024 10:32:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[brasov]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cluj]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[oradea]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://bucharestdailynews.com/?p=3456</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Brasov is considered the most attractive city in Romania, while Cluj-Napoca ranks second, according to the Urban Attractiveness Index conducted by the Institute for Cities of Vision (IOV). The national top 10 best cities to live continues with Oradea (3rd), Sibiu (4th), Timișoara (5th), Constanța (6th), Constanța (6th), Bucharest (7th), Iași (8th), Alba Iulia (9th) [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com/romanias-most-attractive-cities-brasov-cluj-napoca-and-oradea/">Romania&#8217;s most attractive cities? Brasov, Cluj-Napoca and Oradea</a> appeared first on <a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com">Bucharest Daily News</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p class="has-drop-cap">Brasov is considered the most attractive city in Romania, while Cluj-Napoca ranks second, according to the Urban Attractiveness Index conducted by the Institute for Cities of Vision (IOV).</p>



<p>The national top 10 best cities to live continues with Oradea (3rd), Sibiu (4th), Timișoara (5th), Constanța (6th), Constanța (6th), <a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com/metro/">Bucharest</a> (7th), Iași (8th), Alba Iulia (9th) and Piatra Neamț (10th).</p>



<p>At the opposite, the least attractive cities to live in or move to are Vaslui (41st), Slobozia (40th), Călărași (39th), Slatina (38th), Giurgiu (37th), Focșani (36th), Reșița (35th) and Drobeta Turnu Severin (34th).</p>



<p>The two main indicators analyzed are the city as a desirable place to move to, which reflects people&#8217;s subjective and emotional perceptions, and the quality of city life, which provides an overall assessment of a city&#8217;s reputation.</p>



<p>The study shows a strong correlation between the intention to move to a city and how people perceive the quality of life in that city, which confirms that municipalities perceived as having a high quality of life are usually also the most attractive destinations to move to.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-wp-embed is-provider-bucharest-daily-news wp-block-embed-bucharest-daily-news"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="f23bJseFwt"><a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com/over-60000-children-in-romania-have-one-or-both-parents-working-abroad/">Over 60,000 children in Romania have one or both parents working abroad</a></blockquote><iframe loading="lazy" class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted"  title="&#8220;Over 60,000 children in Romania have one or both parents working abroad&#8221; &#8212; Bucharest Daily News" src="https://bucharestdailynews.com/over-60000-children-in-romania-have-one-or-both-parents-working-abroad/embed/#?secret=XggDDv1I7r#?secret=f23bJseFwt" data-secret="f23bJseFwt" width="600" height="338" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe>
</div></figure>
<p>The post <a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com/romanias-most-attractive-cities-brasov-cluj-napoca-and-oradea/">Romania&#8217;s most attractive cities? Brasov, Cluj-Napoca and Oradea</a> appeared first on <a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com">Bucharest Daily News</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Romania is among the countries with the largest share of the population on TikTok</title>
		<link>https://bucharestdailynews.com/romania-is-among-the-countries-with-the-largest-share-of-the-population-on-tiktok/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Cristian Hatis]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2024 13:01:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TikTok]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://bucharestdailynews.com/?p=3379</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>At the end of 2023, Romania ranked fourth in the European Union by the largest share of people using the Chinese app TikTok, with 39% percent of the total population. Our country is only surpassed in this ranking by Luxembourg (46% TikTok users out of the total population), Ireland (42% TikTok users out of the [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com/romania-is-among-the-countries-with-the-largest-share-of-the-population-on-tiktok/">Romania is among the countries with the largest share of the population on TikTok</a> appeared first on <a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com">Bucharest Daily News</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p class="has-drop-cap">At the end of 2023, Romania ranked fourth in the European Union by the largest share of people using the Chinese app TikTok, with 39% percent of the total population.</p>



<p>Our country is only surpassed in this ranking by Luxembourg (46% TikTok users out of the total population), Ireland (42% TikTok users out of the total population) and Spain (40% TikTok users out of the total population).</p>



<p>On the other end of the ranking, we have Slovakia (where only 17% of population use TikTok), the Czech Republic (19% of the population use TikTok), Slovenia, and Denmark (24% of the population in each country uses TikTok).</p>



<p>The analysis was carried out by <a href="https://www.europeancorrespondent.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">The European Correspondent</a> using public TikTok data presented in a report published at the end of last year. The app has more than 1.5 billion users globally.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-wp-embed is-provider-bucharest-daily-news wp-block-embed-bucharest-daily-news"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="ILUwOnckcb"><a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com/domeniile-ostrov-winery-expects-sales-and-production-to-increase-this-year/">Domeniile Ostrov Winery expects sales and production to increase this year</a></blockquote><iframe loading="lazy" class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted"  title="&#8220;Domeniile Ostrov Winery expects sales and production to increase this year&#8221; &#8212; Bucharest Daily News" src="https://bucharestdailynews.com/domeniile-ostrov-winery-expects-sales-and-production-to-increase-this-year/embed/#?secret=lFlLz1jWQl#?secret=ILUwOnckcb" data-secret="ILUwOnckcb" width="600" height="338" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe>
</div></figure>
<p>The post <a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com/romania-is-among-the-countries-with-the-largest-share-of-the-population-on-tiktok/">Romania is among the countries with the largest share of the population on TikTok</a> appeared first on <a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com">Bucharest Daily News</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Historic day for LGBTQIA+ community in Romania, biggest pride event ever</title>
		<link>https://bucharestdailynews.com/historic-day-for-lgbtqia-community-in-romania-biggest-pride-event-ever/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Cristian Hatis]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2024 20:56:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LGBT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[march]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://bucharestdailynews.com/?p=3326</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The Bucharest Pride 2024 march, which took place in the capital on Saturday, was the biggest ever, with around 27,000 people taking part in this event for the Romanian LGBTQIA+ community. The march started at the intersection of Victoriei Square and Calea Victoriei, and continued on the route Calea Victoriei &#8211; United Nations Bridge &#8211; [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com/historic-day-for-lgbtqia-community-in-romania-biggest-pride-event-ever/">Historic day for LGBTQIA+ community in Romania, biggest pride event ever</a> appeared first on <a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com">Bucharest Daily News</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p class="has-drop-cap">The Bucharest Pride 2024 march, which took place in the capital on Saturday, was the biggest ever, with around 27,000 people taking part in this event for the Romanian LGBTQIA+ community.</p>



<p>The march started at the intersection of Victoriei Square and Calea Victoriei, and continued on the route Calea Victoriei &#8211; United Nations Bridge &#8211; United Nations Bd. &#8211; crossing Bd. Libertății &#8211; Izvor Park.</p>



<p>Bucharest Pride 2024 march participants displayed several messages about equality, love, peace, and respect, offered LGBTQIA+ flags to passers-by and were supported by a good number of onlookers.</p>



<p>An Accept NGO survey shows that 56% of Romanians say they support civil marriage and civil partnerships for <a href="https://savorbimdespresex.ro/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">same-sex families</a>, and 72% say their heterosexual families would have nothing to lose if LGBTQIA+ families had equal rights.</p>



<p>Romania is generally conservative on lesbian, gay, bisexual, or transgender (<a href="https://savorbimdespresex.ro/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">LGBT</a>) rights, so people in these categories may face different legal barriers than the rest of the citizens.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-gallery alignfull has-nested-images columns-2 is-cropped wp-block-gallery-1 is-layout-flex wp-block-gallery-is-layout-flex">
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="683" data-id="3328" src="https://bucharestdailynews.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/Bucharest-Pride-2024-flag-1024x683.jpeg" alt="" class="wp-image-3328"/></figure>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="683" data-id="3331" src="https://bucharestdailynews.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/Bucharest-Pride-2024-march-1024x683.jpeg" alt="" class="wp-image-3331"/></figure>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="683" data-id="3329" src="https://bucharestdailynews.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/Bucharest-Pride-2024-Love-is-Love-1024x683.jpeg" alt="" class="wp-image-3329"/></figure>
</figure>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-wp-embed is-provider-bucharest-daily-news wp-block-embed-bucharest-daily-news"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="ZK9FCeKlTu"><a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com/additional-s-70-black-hawk-helicopter-for-department-of-emergency-situations/">Additional S-70 Black Hawk Helicopter for Department of Emergency Situations</a></blockquote><iframe loading="lazy" class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted"  title="&#8220;Additional S-70 Black Hawk Helicopter for Department of Emergency Situations&#8221; &#8212; Bucharest Daily News" src="https://bucharestdailynews.com/additional-s-70-black-hawk-helicopter-for-department-of-emergency-situations/embed/#?secret=HCDs5mPTql#?secret=ZK9FCeKlTu" data-secret="ZK9FCeKlTu" width="600" height="338" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe>
</div></figure>
<p>The post <a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com/historic-day-for-lgbtqia-community-in-romania-biggest-pride-event-ever/">Historic day for LGBTQIA+ community in Romania, biggest pride event ever</a> appeared first on <a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com">Bucharest Daily News</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
