<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Bucharest Daily News &#8226; Latest News Romania</title>
	<atom:link href="https://bucharestdailynews.com/news/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://bucharestdailynews.com/news/</link>
	<description>News from Bucharest and Romania</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 08:28:58 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.8.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://bucharestdailynews.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/cropped-bucharest-daily-news-icon-black-32x32.webp</url>
	<title>Bucharest Daily News &#8226; Latest News Romania</title>
	<link>https://bucharestdailynews.com/news/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>George Simion leads first round of Romanian presidential election rerun</title>
		<link>https://bucharestdailynews.com/george-simion-leads-first-round-of-romanian-presidential-election-rerun/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Cristian Hatis]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 08:28:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Election]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[elections]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[politics]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://bucharestdailynews.com/?p=4743</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Voter turnout at polling stations within the country was 47,80%. Including votes from abroad, total turnout was 53,21%, almost 10 million voters (9.571.740)</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com/george-simion-leads-first-round-of-romanian-presidential-election-rerun/">George Simion leads first round of Romanian presidential election rerun</a> appeared first on <a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com">Bucharest Daily News</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p class="has-drop-cap">Romania has entered a decisive phase in its presidential election process after the first round of the highly anticipated rerun concluded on May 4. Nationalist candidate <strong>George Simion</strong>, leader of the Alliance for the Union of Romanians (AUR), emerged as the frontrunner, securing 40.96% of the national vote.</p>



<p>Simion, who ran a campaign centered on nationalism, traditional values, and Euroscepticism, will now face independent, pro-European candidate <strong>Nicușor Dan</strong>, who garnered 20.99%, in the runoff scheduled for May 18. Dan, the mayor of <strong><a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com/metro/">Bucharest</a></strong>, is widely seen as a moderate voice and has already begun consolidating support from centrist and liberal parties in a bid to counter Simion’s surge.</p>



<p>Former Liberal Party leader <strong>Crin Antonescu</strong> trailed narrowly behind Dan with 20.51%, failing to reach the second round, and his former ally, Victor Ponta (ex-President of Social Democratic Party), was voted by 13,05% of voters. The remaining votes were divided among several minor candidates.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-a-historic-rerun">A Historic Rerun</h3>



<p>This election rerun follows the annulment of the original November 2024 vote by Romania’s Constitutional Court, citing unprecedented levels of foreign interference. Intelligence reports and independent investigations found credible evidence of Russian hybrid attacks, including coordinated disinformation campaigns and cyber intrusion aimed at swaying public opinion.</p>



<p>That annulled vote had seen Călin Georgescu take an early lead before the results were thrown out. Georgescu was later disqualified from the rerun due to alleged campaign irregularities and a criminal investigation into his finances.</p>



<p>Simion stepped in as a replacement candidate for the nationalist bloc, quickly consolidating support from Georgescu’s base. His performance in the diaspora vote was particularly strong, winning over 61% of overseas ballots cast.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-a-divided-electorate">A Divided Electorate</h3>



<p>The results underscore a deepening divide in Romanian politics between a growing nationalist current and a pro-European mainstream. Simion’s critics warn that his rise may jeopardize Romania’s commitments to the European Union and NATO, as well as its stance on regional security amid Russia’s continued aggression in Ukraine.</p>



<p>In contrast, Nicușor Dan has vowed to strengthen Romania’s Western alliances and uphold democratic norms. Speaking on Sunday night, Dan said, <em>“This election is not just about Romania’s next president; it’s about the kind of country we want to live in.”</em></p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-what-s-next">What’s Next?</h3>



<p>The next two weeks will see a heated campaign as both camps rally their bases. Analysts suggest Dan will need near-unified backing from the center-left and moderate right to overcome Simion’s strong first-round momentum.</p>



<p>The runoff vote will take place on May 18, with international observers already deployed to ensure a free and fair electoral process. The outcome is expected to have profound implications for the country’s geopolitical alignment, democratic institutions, and social cohesion.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-wp-embed is-provider-bucharest-daily-news wp-block-embed-bucharest-daily-news"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="d8QGXMymhE"><a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com/bucharest-traffic-is-getting-worse-romanias-capital-ranks-5th-at-congestion-level-in-the-world/">Bucharest traffic is getting worse! Romania&#8217;s capital ranks 5th at congestion level in the world</a></blockquote><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted"  title="&#8220;Bucharest traffic is getting worse! Romania&#8217;s capital ranks 5th at congestion level in the world&#8221; &#8212; Bucharest Daily News" src="https://bucharestdailynews.com/bucharest-traffic-is-getting-worse-romanias-capital-ranks-5th-at-congestion-level-in-the-world/embed/#?secret=MePzOTlZp3#?secret=d8QGXMymhE" data-secret="d8QGXMymhE" width="600" height="338" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe>
</div></figure>
<p>The post <a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com/george-simion-leads-first-round-of-romanian-presidential-election-rerun/">George Simion leads first round of Romanian presidential election rerun</a> appeared first on <a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com">Bucharest Daily News</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>George Simion is in the second round, while Crin Antonescu and Nicușor Dan are ”in the playoff” for the presidency</title>
		<link>https://bucharestdailynews.com/george-simion-is-in-the-second-round-while-crin-antonescu-and-nicusor-dan-are-in-the-playoff-for-the-presidency/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Cristian Hatis]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 04 May 2025 19:28:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Election]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[elections]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[politics]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://bucharestdailynews.com/?p=4739</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Surprises—but not really—in the first round of the presidential elections. George Simion (AUR) gets the most votes and will face off against either Nicușor Dan (Independent) or Crin Antonescu (PSD-PNL-UDMR Alliance), who are fighting to the last vote. According to data from an exit poll conducted by Avangarde at 7:00 PM, George Simion managed to [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com/george-simion-is-in-the-second-round-while-crin-antonescu-and-nicusor-dan-are-in-the-playoff-for-the-presidency/">George Simion is in the second round, while Crin Antonescu and Nicușor Dan are ”in the playoff” for the presidency</a> appeared first on <a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com">Bucharest Daily News</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p class="has-drop-cap">Surprises—but not really—in the first round of the presidential elections. George Simion (AUR) gets the most votes and will face off against either Nicușor Dan (Independent) or Crin Antonescu (PSD-PNL-UDMR Alliance), who are fighting to the last vote.</p>



<p>According to data from an exit poll conducted by Avangarde at 7:00 PM, George Simion managed to attract 30% of the vote, followed by Crin Antonescu and Nicușor Dan, each with 23%, and Victor Ponta (Independent) with 15%. Elena Lasconi (USR) only managed to convince 4% of the voters.</p>



<p>Another exit poll, conducted by CURS at 7:00 PM, shows George Simion was preferred by 33% of those who voted today, followed by Crin Antonescu with 22.90%, Nicușor Dan (20.90%), Victor Ponta (14.70%), and Elena Lasconi (4.7%).</p>



<p>The INSCOP poll also places George Simion in first for the presidential runoff, with 36.2% of today’s vote, followed in second place by the governing coalition’s candidate, Crin Antonescu – 21.5%. In third place is the independent Nicușor Dan, with 20.6%, followed by Victor Ponta with 17.1% and Elena Lasconi – 2.5%.</p>



<p><em>“I’m experienced enough to know that election victories are not decided by exit polls, and we cannot commit to anything based on them. We must wait to count every vote. When all votes have been counted and the results are officially in, we will talk about winners and losers,”</em> said <strong>Crin Antonescu</strong>, the candidate of the PSD-PNL-UDMR alliance, after polls closed.</p>



<p>He went on to thank <em>“everyone who gave me their vote. Thank you. I feel honored, and if this vote becomes a mandate to serve as President of Romania, I will carry it with the hope that they placed in me.”</em></p>



<p>In a recorded video message, <strong>George Simion</strong> said in his usual style: <em>“I want to thank you, brothers and sisters from here and everywhere. Together we made history today. We are approaching an exceptional result, far beyond what the system&#8217;s TV stations are showing (…) Congratulations! You are the winners! Today, the Romanian people voted—today the Romanian people spoke. It’s time to be heard!”</em></p>



<p><em>“Democracy is about communities—their problems, their aspirations—and tonight I want to congratulate the voter communities of each of my opponents for the debate they carried out, especially on social media, which in my opinion was much more substantial than the one we politicians managed to produce,”</em> said <strong>Nicușor Dan</strong> after the election process ended.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-how-many-people-voted">How many people voted</h2>



<p>Voter turnout at polling stations within the country was 47,80 %. Including votes from abroad, total turnout was 53,21 %, almost 10 million voters (9.571.740). In November 2024, at the same time of day, the turnout in the country was 51.19%, with 9,219,366 Romanians voting.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-wp-embed is-provider-bucharest-daily-news wp-block-embed-bucharest-daily-news"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="LDlThCvteM"><a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com/united-states-removes-romania-from-visa-waiver-program/">United States removes Romania from Visa Waiver Program</a></blockquote><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted"  title="&#8220;United States removes Romania from Visa Waiver Program&#8221; &#8212; Bucharest Daily News" src="https://bucharestdailynews.com/united-states-removes-romania-from-visa-waiver-program/embed/#?secret=lKdviPnimx#?secret=LDlThCvteM" data-secret="LDlThCvteM" width="600" height="338" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe>
</div></figure>
<p>The post <a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com/george-simion-is-in-the-second-round-while-crin-antonescu-and-nicusor-dan-are-in-the-playoff-for-the-presidency/">George Simion is in the second round, while Crin Antonescu and Nicușor Dan are ”in the playoff” for the presidency</a> appeared first on <a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com">Bucharest Daily News</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>It’s now harder to get Romanian citizenship. Language proficiency is a must!</title>
		<link>https://bucharestdailynews.com/its-now-harder-to-get-romanian-citizenship-language-proficiency-is-a-must/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Cristian Hatis]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 19 Apr 2025 07:35:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[citizenship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Romanian]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://bucharestdailynews.com/?p=4663</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>In 2024, 50,350 applications were submitted, yet none were approved by year’s end</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com/its-now-harder-to-get-romanian-citizenship-language-proficiency-is-a-must/">It’s now harder to get Romanian citizenship. Language proficiency is a must!</a> appeared first on <a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com">Bucharest Daily News</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p class="has-drop-cap">The process of acquiring Romanian citizenship has seen major changes in recent years, and the numbers tell a striking story. From 2018 to 2024, application trends fluctuated, with an initial rise followed by a steep decline in approval rates—reflecting a shift toward stricter requirements.</p>



<p>In 2018, Romania received 93,787 citizenship applications, with an impressive 88% approval rate. However, by 2023, the landscape had drastically changed: only 0.37% of the 38,981 submitted files were approved, with the vast majority still under review.</p>



<p>In 2024, 50,350 applications were submitted, yet none were approved by year’s end. As of March 2025, the National Authority for Citizenship (ANC) has received an additional 3,976 files, with no approvals issued to date, according to data provided by the Margarit &amp; Associates Romanian Law Firm.</p>



<p>Among the most notable changes is the introduction of stricter language requirements, thus a certificate from a Romanian higher education institution or another accredited authority is mandatory to prove language competence, whether applying for naturalization or reacquisition of citizenship.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-romanian-citizenship-by-birth-the-easiest-path-to-nationality">Romanian Citizenship by Birth: The Easiest Path to Nationality</h2>



<p>For those eligible, acquiring Romanian citizenship by birth is the most straightforward route. The country’s citizenship laws grant automatic citizenship to individuals born on Romanian territory, with a few exceptions defined by specific legal provisions.</p>



<p>Children born abroad to at least one Romanian parent are also entitled to citizenship by birth, regardless of where they are born. In these cases, the process is significantly simpler compared to naturalization or reacquisition, as it does not require filing a full application or meeting language proficiency requirements.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-how-to-obtain-romanian-citizenship-by-naturalization">How to Obtain Romanian Citizenship by Naturalization</h2>



<p>Naturalization in Romania offers a legal pathway for foreign nationals to gain Romanian citizenship, but only if they meet specific criteria set by the state. Key requirements include living in Romania for at least 8 years (or 5 years if married to a Romanian citizen), demonstrating proficiency in the Romanian language (minimum B1 level), and showing integration into Romanian society and culture.</p>



<p>To prove eligibility, applicants must submit supporting documents such as employment records, evidence of social integration, and proof of good legal standing. These documents are essential to demonstrate the applicant’s ability to actively engage in Romanian social and cultural life.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-reacquiring-romanian-citizenship">Reacquiring Romanian Citizenship</h2>



<p>Individuals who previously held Romanian citizenship but lost it, either due to emigration or voluntary renunciation, can apply to reacquire their citizenship through the National Authority for Citizenship. The loss of citizenship may have been caused by older laws or personal choices, and each case must be reviewed before reinstatement.</p>



<p>Reacquisition of Romanian citizenship involves an administrative process that allows applicants to regain their status, provided they meet specific requirements. These include proving residency in Romania, undergoing background checks to determine the reason for the loss of citizenship, and demonstrating Romanian language proficiency.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-wp-embed is-provider-bucharest-daily-news wp-block-embed-bucharest-daily-news"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="801Sv16bcO"><a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com/individual-consumption-in-romania-surpassed-that-of-poland-and-the-czech-republic/">Individual consumption in Romania surpassed that of Poland and the Czech Republic</a></blockquote><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted"  title="&#8220;Individual consumption in Romania surpassed that of Poland and the Czech Republic&#8221; &#8212; Bucharest Daily News" src="https://bucharestdailynews.com/individual-consumption-in-romania-surpassed-that-of-poland-and-the-czech-republic/embed/#?secret=JoXUjSfvNg#?secret=801Sv16bcO" data-secret="801Sv16bcO" width="600" height="338" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe>
</div></figure>



<p></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com/its-now-harder-to-get-romanian-citizenship-language-proficiency-is-a-must/">It’s now harder to get Romanian citizenship. Language proficiency is a must!</a> appeared first on <a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com">Bucharest Daily News</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Another NATO exercise in Romania. Dacian Spring to start on May 5th</title>
		<link>https://bucharestdailynews.com/another-nato-exercise-in-romania-dacian-spring-to-start-on-may-5th/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Cristian Hatis]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 19 Apr 2025 07:03:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[army]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://bucharestdailynews.com/?p=4659</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Around 4,000 military personnel and 913 technical means from 10 allied nations (Belgium, Bulgaria, France, Italy, Luxembourg, North Macedonia, Poland, Portugal, Romania and Spain) are participating in the multinational exercise Dacian Spring 2025 in Romania, from May 5-23. Initial reports indicate that the first allied troops entered the country on April 16, through the Nădlac [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com/another-nato-exercise-in-romania-dacian-spring-to-start-on-may-5th/">Another NATO exercise in Romania. Dacian Spring to start on May 5th</a> appeared first on <a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com">Bucharest Daily News</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p class="has-drop-cap">Around 4,000 military personnel and 913 technical means from 10 allied nations (Belgium, Bulgaria, France, Italy, Luxembourg, North Macedonia, Poland, Portugal, Romania and Spain) are participating in the multinational exercise Dacian Spring 2025 in Romania, from May 5-23.</p>



<p>Initial reports indicate that the first allied troops entered the country on April 16, through the Nădlac border crossing, heading towards the Bogata training ground. The deployment of the Belgian maneuver battalion on Romanian territory within DASP 25 it is the first-of-its-kind.</p>



<p>The exercise is planned and led by Headquarters Multinational Division South-East (MND-SE HQ) and will be simultaneously conducted in Smârdan, Cincu, Capu Midia, Bogata and Frecăței Training Areas.</p>



<p>The exercise aims to practice collective defense operations and enhance the integration of participating forces within the command and control structure of the Multinational Division South-East (HQ MND-SE)</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-wp-embed is-provider-bucharest-daily-news wp-block-embed-bucharest-daily-news"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="VFf2AlI8mH"><a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com/ilie-bolojan-the-interim-president-met-with-an-8-member-delegation-from-the-us-congress/">Ilie Bolojan, the interim president, met with an 8-member delegation from the US Congress</a></blockquote><iframe loading="lazy" class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted"  title="&#8220;Ilie Bolojan, the interim president, met with an 8-member delegation from the US Congress&#8221; &#8212; Bucharest Daily News" src="https://bucharestdailynews.com/ilie-bolojan-the-interim-president-met-with-an-8-member-delegation-from-the-us-congress/embed/#?secret=xQANrDZnEk#?secret=VFf2AlI8mH" data-secret="VFf2AlI8mH" width="600" height="338" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe>
</div></figure>
<p>The post <a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com/another-nato-exercise-in-romania-dacian-spring-to-start-on-may-5th/">Another NATO exercise in Romania. Dacian Spring to start on May 5th</a> appeared first on <a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com">Bucharest Daily News</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ilie Bolojan, the interim president, met with an 8-member delegation from the US Congress</title>
		<link>https://bucharestdailynews.com/ilie-bolojan-the-interim-president-met-with-an-8-member-delegation-from-the-us-congress/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Cristian Hatis]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 21:15:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[presidency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[USA]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://bucharestdailynews.com/?p=4654</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The US delegation also met with Prime Minister Marcel Ciolacu and Romanian parliamentarians, with the aim of strengthening bilateral ties</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com/ilie-bolojan-the-interim-president-met-with-an-8-member-delegation-from-the-us-congress/">Ilie Bolojan, the interim president, met with an 8-member delegation from the US Congress</a> appeared first on <a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com">Bucharest Daily News</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p class="has-drop-cap">Romania&#8217;s interim president, Ilie Bolojan, met with an 8-member delegation from the US Congress in Bucharest. Discussions focused on strengthening the US presence in Romania, especially in the context of Black Sea security challenges.</p>



<p>President Ilie Bolojan reaffirmed Romania&#8217;s firm commitment to the Strategic Partnership with the United States, emphasising that it is a key element of foreign policy and national security architecture. He also underlined that close cooperation with the US is essential for effective deterrence and that Romania is actively contributing to the security of NATO&#8217;s eastern flank.</p>



<p>Another topic of the discussions was the progress of Romania&#8217;s inclusion in the Visa Waiver Programme. Mr Ilie Bolojan expresses its full willingness to cooperate with the American authorities in order to finalise this process within a reasonable timeframe and with a positive outcome.</p>



<p>He also underlined the common interest in developing the economic dimension of the strategic partnership by attracting US investment and expanding trade cooperation. In the current context of the Romanian economy, there is a significant potential for deepening bilateral economic relations.</p>



<p>The delegation included eight members of Congress representing both political parties: Vern Buchanan (Republican), Dina Titus (Democrat), Lloyd Doggett (Democrat), Ted Lieu (Democrat), Neal Dunn (Republican), Ilhan Omar (Democrat), Anna Paulina Luna (Republican) and Andy Ogles (Republican).</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-wp-embed is-provider-bucharest-daily-news wp-block-embed-bucharest-daily-news"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="4EShTsxcME"><a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com/authorities-concerned-about-a-significant-surge-in-measles-cases/">Authorities, concerned about a significant surge in measles cases</a></blockquote><iframe loading="lazy" class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted"  title="&#8220;Authorities, concerned about a significant surge in measles cases&#8221; &#8212; Bucharest Daily News" src="https://bucharestdailynews.com/authorities-concerned-about-a-significant-surge-in-measles-cases/embed/#?secret=UQ1kmtgSYm#?secret=4EShTsxcME" data-secret="4EShTsxcME" width="600" height="338" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe>
</div></figure>
<p>The post <a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com/ilie-bolojan-the-interim-president-met-with-an-8-member-delegation-from-the-us-congress/">Ilie Bolojan, the interim president, met with an 8-member delegation from the US Congress</a> appeared first on <a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com">Bucharest Daily News</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Authorities, concerned about a significant surge in measles cases</title>
		<link>https://bucharestdailynews.com/authorities-concerned-about-a-significant-surge-in-measles-cases/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Cristian Hatis]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 20:52:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[health]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://bucharestdailynews.com/?p=4650</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Authorities are concerned about a significant surge in measles cases, attributed to low vaccination coverage. Romania reported the highest number of cases in Europe for 2024, with 30,692, followed by Kazakhstan with 28,147. Less than 80% of eligible children in Romania were vaccinated with MCV1 in 2023 – far below the 95% coverage rate required [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com/authorities-concerned-about-a-significant-surge-in-measles-cases/">Authorities, concerned about a significant surge in measles cases</a> appeared first on <a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com">Bucharest Daily News</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p class="has-drop-cap">Authorities are concerned about a significant surge in measles cases, attributed to low vaccination coverage. Romania reported the highest number of cases in Europe for 2024, with 30,692, followed by Kazakhstan with 28,147.</p>



<p>Less than 80% of eligible children in Romania were vaccinated with MCV1 in 2023 – far below the 95% coverage rate required to retain herd immunity, the same level as countries like Bosnia and Herzegovina, Montenegro, and North Macedonia.</p>



<p>According to an analysis by WHO and the United Nations Children’s Fund (UNICEF), 127.350 measles cases were reported in the European Region for 2024, double the number of cases reported for 2023 and the highest number since 1997.</p>



<p>Children under 5 accounted for more than 40% of reported cases in the region – comprising 53 countries in Europe and central Asia. More than half of the reported cases required hospitalization. A total of 38 deaths have been reported, based on preliminary data received as of 6 March 2025.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-wp-embed is-provider-bucharest-daily-news wp-block-embed-bucharest-daily-news"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="OUj9fHo9RX"><a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com/half-of-romanians-aged-over-40-have-dental-treatments-with-heavy-metal-fillings/">Half of Romanians aged over 40 have dental treatments with heavy metal fillings</a></blockquote><iframe loading="lazy" class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted"  title="&#8220;Half of Romanians aged over 40 have dental treatments with heavy metal fillings&#8221; &#8212; Bucharest Daily News" src="https://bucharestdailynews.com/half-of-romanians-aged-over-40-have-dental-treatments-with-heavy-metal-fillings/embed/#?secret=oGrkALTQhR#?secret=OUj9fHo9RX" data-secret="OUj9fHo9RX" width="600" height="338" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe>
</div></figure>
<p>The post <a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com/authorities-concerned-about-a-significant-surge-in-measles-cases/">Authorities, concerned about a significant surge in measles cases</a> appeared first on <a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com">Bucharest Daily News</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Presidential Elections 2025. Who are the 11 candidates in the race for the Cotroceni Palace</title>
		<link>https://bucharestdailynews.com/presidential-elections-2025-who-are-the-11-candidates-in-the-race-for-the-cotroceni-palace/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Cristian Hatis]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 23 Mar 2025 10:36:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Election]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[elections]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[politics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[presidency]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://bucharestdailynews.com/?p=4564</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The first round of voting is set for May 4, 2025, with a potential runoff on May 18 if no candidate secures an absolute majority</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com/presidential-elections-2025-who-are-the-11-candidates-in-the-race-for-the-cotroceni-palace/">Presidential Elections 2025. Who are the 11 candidates in the race for the Cotroceni Palace</a> appeared first on <a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com">Bucharest Daily News</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p class="has-drop-cap">After the December 2024 presidential elections were canceled, Romanians are called to the polls on May 4th and May 18, 2025 to elect their president. They can choose from eleven candidates, including four independents. For the first time after 1989, the Social Democratic Party (PSD) does not have its own candidate.</p>



<p>The presidential elections feature a list of 11 candidates approved by the Central Electoral Bureau (BEC) and validated by the Constitutional Court of Romania (CCR). On March 23, 2025, the BEC also established the order of candidates on the ballots.</p>



<ol class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>George Simion</strong> &#8211; Leader of the far-right Alliance for the Union of Romanians (AUR), a prominent nationalist figure, declared persona non grata in Moldova and Ukraine.</li>



<li><strong>Crin Antonescu</strong> &#8211; Former leader of the National Liberal Party (PNL), proposed as the single candidate of the pro-European Romania Forward Electoral Alliance, which includes PSD, PNL, and UDMR.</li>



<li><strong>Elena Lasconi</strong> &#8211; Representing the center-right Save Romania Union (USR), she previously advanced to the runoff in the annulled 2024 election, after collecting over 2 million votes in the first round.</li>



<li><strong>Cristian Terheș</strong> &#8211; A candidate from the far-right Romanian National Conservative Party (PNCR).</li>



<li><strong>Lavinia Șandru</strong> &#8211; Independent candidate.</li>



<li><strong>Victor Ponta</strong> &#8211; Former Prime Minister and leader of the PRO Romania party.</li>



<li><strong>Sebastian Popescu</strong> &#8211; Independent candidate</li>



<li><strong>Silviu Predoiu</strong> &#8211; Former head of the Romanian Foreign Intelligence Service (SIE), running as an independent.</li>



<li><strong>John Ion Banu Muscel</strong> &#8211; A former graduate of the Polytechnic University of Bucharest who emigrated to the USA in 1985.</li>



<li><strong>Daniel Funeriu</strong> &#8211; Former Education Minister, possibly running as an independent or with a smaller party.</li>



<li><strong>Nicușor Dan</strong> &#8211; Current Mayor of Bucharest, in a second term, running as an independent candidate.</li>
</ol>



<p>Notably, <a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com/constitutional-court-rejected-calin-georgescus-appeal-he-cant-run-for-president/">Călin Georgescu</a>, who led the annulled 2024 election&#8217;s first round, was barred from running in this rerun due to allegations of Russian interference and subsequent legal challenges, including charges of incitement and support for fascist groups.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-wp-embed is-provider-bucharest-daily-news wp-block-embed-bucharest-daily-news"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="pv1vB1jT7H"><a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com/tate-brothers-returning-to-romania-on-a-private-plane-innocent-men-dont-run/">Tate brothers returning to Romania on a private plane: ”Innocent men don’t run!”</a></blockquote><iframe loading="lazy" class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted"  title="&#8220;Tate brothers returning to Romania on a private plane: ”Innocent men don’t run!”&#8221; &#8212; Bucharest Daily News" src="https://bucharestdailynews.com/tate-brothers-returning-to-romania-on-a-private-plane-innocent-men-dont-run/embed/#?secret=XzcftvCyak#?secret=pv1vB1jT7H" data-secret="pv1vB1jT7H" width="600" height="338" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe>
</div></figure>
<p>The post <a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com/presidential-elections-2025-who-are-the-11-candidates-in-the-race-for-the-cotroceni-palace/">Presidential Elections 2025. Who are the 11 candidates in the race for the Cotroceni Palace</a> appeared first on <a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com">Bucharest Daily News</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Tate brothers returning to Romania on a private plane: ”Innocent men don’t run!”</title>
		<link>https://bucharestdailynews.com/tate-brothers-returning-to-romania-on-a-private-plane-innocent-men-dont-run/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Cristian Hatis]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 15:16:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[airport]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[andrew tate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tate]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://bucharestdailynews.com/?p=4551</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Brothers Andrew and Tristan Tate are returning to Romania from the United States of America on a private plane, landing in Bucharest on Saturday morning, around 3:00 AM, Boarding Pass reports. The aircraft is a Gulfstream G650ER operated by Qatar Executive. The information was confirmed by Andrew Tate in a post on the X platform: [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com/tate-brothers-returning-to-romania-on-a-private-plane-innocent-men-dont-run/">Tate brothers returning to Romania on a private plane: ”Innocent men don’t run!”</a> appeared first on <a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com">Bucharest Daily News</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p class="has-drop-cap">Brothers Andrew and Tristan Tate are returning to Romania from the United States of America on a private plane, landing in <a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com/metro/">Bucharest</a> on Saturday morning, around 3:00 AM, <a href="https://boardingpass.ro/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Boarding Pass</a> reports. The aircraft is a Gulfstream G650ER operated by Qatar Executive.</p>



<p>The information was confirmed by Andrew Tate in a <a href="https://x.com/Cobratate/status/1903072252243087512" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">post on the X platform</a>: <em>”Spending 185,000 dollars on a private jet across the Atlantic to sign one single piece of paper in Romania. Innocent men don’t run. They clear their name in court”</em>.</p>



<p>On February 27, the Tate brothers left Romania for the USA with the consent of the DIICOT prosecutor investigating their rape case. The parties agreed at the time that they would return to Romania under judicial supervision.</p>



<p>Andrew and Tristan Tate, with dual British and American citizenship, were indicted by DIICOT on June 20, 2023, on charges of constituting an organized criminal group, trafficking in persons, rape, illegal access to a computer system, assault, or other violence.</p>



<p>Andrew Tate is a well-known influencer with more than 10 million followers on the X network, where he promotes men&#8217;s rights, homophobic and racist messages. An Donald Trump fan and former professional kick-boxer, he was born in the US living in Romania for several years.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-wp-embed is-provider-bucharest-daily-news wp-block-embed-bucharest-daily-news"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Mxwy1aZhzt"><a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com/luxury-brand-zegna-opens-a-store-in-bucharest-near-the-atheneum/">Luxury brand ZEGNA opens a store in Bucharest, near the Atheneum</a></blockquote><iframe loading="lazy" class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted"  title="&#8220;Luxury brand ZEGNA opens a store in Bucharest, near the Atheneum&#8221; &#8212; Bucharest Daily News" src="https://bucharestdailynews.com/luxury-brand-zegna-opens-a-store-in-bucharest-near-the-atheneum/embed/#?secret=ExkqoCczvO#?secret=Mxwy1aZhzt" data-secret="Mxwy1aZhzt" width="600" height="338" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe>
</div></figure>
<p>The post <a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com/tate-brothers-returning-to-romania-on-a-private-plane-innocent-men-dont-run/">Tate brothers returning to Romania on a private plane: ”Innocent men don’t run!”</a> appeared first on <a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com">Bucharest Daily News</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Central Electoral Bureau rejected Eurodeputy Diana Șoșoacă candidacy in the presidential elections</title>
		<link>https://bucharestdailynews.com/central-electoral-bureau-rejected-eurodeputy-diana-sosoaca-candidacy-in-the-presidential-elections/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Cristian Hatis]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 15 Mar 2025 10:39:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Election]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[elections]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://bucharestdailynews.com/?p=4517</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Central Electoral Bureau (BEC) rejected Eurodeputy Diana Șoșoacă candidacy in the presidential elections by ten votes against and three in favor. AUR leader George Simion and USR leader Elena Lasconi&#8217;s candidacies were validated. ”AD AUGUSTA PER ANGUSTA &#8211; brilliant results are reached by narrow, tedious paths!”, wrote Diana Șoșoacă on Facebook after the BEC members&#8217; [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com/central-electoral-bureau-rejected-eurodeputy-diana-sosoaca-candidacy-in-the-presidential-elections/">Central Electoral Bureau rejected Eurodeputy Diana Șoșoacă candidacy in the presidential elections</a> appeared first on <a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com">Bucharest Daily News</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p class="has-drop-cap">Central Electoral Bureau (BEC) rejected Eurodeputy Diana Șoșoacă candidacy in the presidential elections by ten votes against and three in favor. AUR leader George Simion and USR leader Elena Lasconi&#8217;s candidacies were validated.</p>



<p><em>”AD AUGUSTA PER ANGUSTA &#8211; brilliant results are reached by narrow, tedious paths!”</em>, wrote Diana Șoșoacă on Facebook after the BEC members&#8217; vote. Șoșoacă candidacy in the presidential elections is rejected for the second time, after November 2024.</p>



<p>Last year, Șoșoacă&#8217;s candidacy was stopped by the Constitutional Court which stated her far-right, xenophobic rhetoric, was incompatible with democratic standards. Miss Șoșoacă is a non-attached member of the European Parliament since 2024.</p>



<p>So far, 14 candidacies have been filed for the upcoming May presidential elections, 4 have been rejected, including that of <a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com/constitutional-court-rejected-calin-georgescus-appeal-he-cant-run-for-president/">Călin Georgescu</a>, and two have become final, those of Crin Antonescu and Bucharest&#8217;s Mayor Nicușor Dan.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-wp-embed is-provider-bucharest-daily-news wp-block-embed-bucharest-daily-news"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="VaCS36Sa6P"><a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com/romania-and-netherlands-launch-joint-investigation-into-theft-of-dacian-artifacts-from-drents-museum/">Romania and Netherlands launch joint investigation into theft of Dacian artifacts from Drents Museum</a></blockquote><iframe loading="lazy" class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted"  title="&#8220;Romania and Netherlands launch joint investigation into theft of Dacian artifacts from Drents Museum&#8221; &#8212; Bucharest Daily News" src="https://bucharestdailynews.com/romania-and-netherlands-launch-joint-investigation-into-theft-of-dacian-artifacts-from-drents-museum/embed/#?secret=jBW4Y5u50K#?secret=VaCS36Sa6P" data-secret="VaCS36Sa6P" width="600" height="338" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe>
</div></figure>
<p>The post <a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com/central-electoral-bureau-rejected-eurodeputy-diana-sosoaca-candidacy-in-the-presidential-elections/">Central Electoral Bureau rejected Eurodeputy Diana Șoșoacă candidacy in the presidential elections</a> appeared first on <a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com">Bucharest Daily News</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Romania is the worst country to rent a car in Europe</title>
		<link>https://bucharestdailynews.com/romania-is-the-worst-country-to-rent-a-car-in-europe/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Cristian Hatis]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 15 Mar 2025 09:48:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cars]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[used cars]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://bucharestdailynews.com/?p=4510</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Top 10 of the worst countries to rent a car in Europe is completed by Latvia, Bulgaria, Italy, Belgium, Cyprus, Poland, Czechia, Slovenia, and Malta</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com/romania-is-the-worst-country-to-rent-a-car-in-europe/">Romania is the worst country to rent a car in Europe</a> appeared first on <a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com">Bucharest Daily News</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p class="has-drop-cap">Romania ranks as the most dangerous European country to rent a car, according to a <a href="https://go-voyager.com/the-most-dangerous-countries-in-the-eu-to-rent-a-car/">Go Voyager study</a>, as it has the lowest road quality, the worst mean speed score of 73, a high fatality rate of 81.1 per 1 million inhabitants, and 2,913 road accidents per 1 million inhabitants a year.</p>



<p>According to World Population Review, the country shows the lowest road quality index of&nbsp;2.96, and has the lowest mean speed score of&nbsp;73, that demonstrates poor road infrastructure, and intense traffic density, which increases traveling time significantly.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The high fatality rate (81.1) and road accident index (2,913) per million inhabitants reveal the careless driving behavior of the local drivers, as well as their failure to properly follow traffic regulations. Additionally, the aforementioned poor road quality and intense traffic can impact the chance of getting into a car accident.</p>



<p>The data from Statista shows, as of&nbsp;2020, most car accidents have happened during the Summer season:&nbsp;2,166&nbsp;cases occurred in&nbsp;June;&nbsp;2,460&nbsp;accidents happened in&nbsp;July; and&nbsp;2,634- in&nbsp;August. The least number of road accidents happened in&nbsp;April&nbsp;(808). The number grows starting from&nbsp;May&nbsp;(1,449) as the country faces a tourist influx.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-wp-embed is-provider-bucharest-daily-news wp-block-embed-bucharest-daily-news"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="2UOkGEdaNx"><a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com/toyota-prius-audi-a8-and-porsche-cayenne-are-the-most-clocked-second-hand-cars-in-romania/">Toyota Prius, Audi A8 and Porsche Cayenne are the most clocked second-hand cars in Romania</a></blockquote><iframe loading="lazy" class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted"  title="&#8220;Toyota Prius, Audi A8 and Porsche Cayenne are the most clocked second-hand cars in Romania&#8221; &#8212; Bucharest Daily News" src="https://bucharestdailynews.com/toyota-prius-audi-a8-and-porsche-cayenne-are-the-most-clocked-second-hand-cars-in-romania/embed/#?secret=MFiGJq8RLj#?secret=2UOkGEdaNx" data-secret="2UOkGEdaNx" width="600" height="338" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe>
</div></figure>
<p>The post <a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com/romania-is-the-worst-country-to-rent-a-car-in-europe/">Romania is the worst country to rent a car in Europe</a> appeared first on <a href="https://bucharestdailynews.com">Bucharest Daily News</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
